Curriculum Vitae Darragh Martin

23 Siul na Habhann, Mill Road, Corbally, Limerick

Tel: 0877810773

daradona10@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/darragh-martin-61417512/

Profile

I have just completed a full stack Software Framework Course from the Code Institute Dublin giving me an in-depth knowledge and information of computer languages. I have a wealth of managerial experience from working in the gaming industry for over 15 years which gave me a taste to learn more about the IT industry I am an open-minded and hard-working team player with excellent communication skills, great attention to detail and an analytical approach. I am a fast learner, reliable and conscientious individual.

Professional Experience

October 2016 - December 2018

Marko Ltd – Director/Secretary of Company

- Was instrumental in the initialising process whereby a very successful sale of the company's business as a going concern as well as a property portfolio associated with it took place.
- Implemented the latest software systems on all machines that calculated real time data to the main company database.
- Overhauled the company's customers database to compile with GDPR regulations
- Incorporated many computer programmes on company database to showcase company profit
 and loss accounts, future projections and latest machine software patches to maintain
 everything up to date to prevent machine shutdowns
- Set up a ticketing system from machines to in house ATM to give customers more control of their withdrawals and more privacy for them

August 2013 – September 2016

Marko Ltd – General Manager

- Interacted with other IT specialists around Europe when machines went down due to server problems and following step by step protocol to get them up and running
- Took charge of all casino operations & management of car park operation
- Successful introduction of technical revamp of systems whereby operations to control accounting feedback from individual gambling machines
- Linked all gaming machines to online jackpots for in house

August 2009 - July 2013

Marko Ltd – Floor Manager

- Devising cash control and accounting systems to assist in assessing and reconciling the performance of diverse casino equipment as regards input of cash and pay out of winnings to casino customers
- Devised and implemented weekly management accounting reports on Excel
- Banking duties control including preparation of lodgements and preparation of invoice payments to suppliers

Preparation of weekly payroll in association with auditors

July 2005 - July 2009

Marko Limited – Floor Supervisor

 Work on floor as supervisor in casino, liaise with customers, dealing with technical problems on casino equipment, cash collections from casino equipment, cash control duties in cashier office, control supervising duties and liaising with all staff on day to day basis and coordinating working rotas

May 2002 to October 2002

Irish Life & Permanent (Dublin) – Internship

- Implemented key data from their client list into spreadsheets
- Weekly board meetings to discuss various issues that needed addressing
- Worked with a small group to implement the Irish Life Census forms to all their employees over the country and to record and implement the data to their database
- Worked with other departments within from HR to Accounting to implement various tasks that needed doing from phone calls, emails, and various data that was requested on behalf of the company

Education and Qualifications

2019 - 2020 - Code Institute Dublin

Diploma in Software Development

Covered HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Popper.js, GitHub, Heroku, JavaScript, Google Maps API, EmailJS, CRUD Operations, Travis CI, Gitpod, AWS 3, AWS IAM, Python, Django, Stripe Payments, PostGres database, SQL, Mongo DB, Flask and User Experience Design (UXD) https://github.com/daradona10?tab=stars- A list of my projects covered here including my

online CV. Feel free to have a look.

I covered 4 projects as part of my course;

Project 1: Designed a gym website which was built using HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap framework along with some JS/JQuery for interactivity. Some of the features were a facilities page, class timetable page with some videos of similar classes, membership options page and a contact page with location map and contact us form.

Project 2: Designed a website for the EURO 2020 Football Championships which alongside using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JQuery, JavaScript and EmailJS was utilising Google Maps API. It allowed users to click on icons on maps to show where games where being held, to also to zoom in on host cities by choosing cities of their choice, match and stadium page and to incorporate users to sign up.

Project 3: Designed a cookbook recipe website that allowed users to view recipes, the preparation methods, ingredients needed and how each dish was prepared. It also allowed the recipes to be edited, deleted and to add more recipes to the site using the CRUD operations (Create, Read, Update and Delete) and displaying data retrieved from a SQL database. The website utilises MongoDB database together with Python code to access and manipulate the data. Flask Framework also used along with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.

Project 4: Designed a fully functioning E-commerce website that allows users to buy football training gear from football tops to shorts and socks by displaying the prices, choosing a size and adding

quantity desired to shopping cart. It then allowed the user to view their contents in the checkout page and amend their contents if necessary before checking out and filling out their details and using a fully functioning Stripe payment system which I was able to set up. This project was to demonstrate Full Stack development of the website. Utilises a PostGres database together with Python code to access and manipulate the data. Visualisation is done with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript where required, utilising the Django Framework. Heroku was used to deploy it, Travis CI for build testing along with AWS 3 for hosting of static and media files and using AWS IAM.

2004 - 2005 - University of Limerick

International Management in Entrepreneurship Honours Degree

1997 - 2002 - American College Dublin

Bachelor of Arts in International Business Honours Degree

Jan – May '02 – Lynn University Boca Raton, Florida

Spent a semester studying at the well renowned university In Boca Raton as part of my degree.

1995 – 1997 – St. Clements College Secondary School, Limerick

1991-1995 - Rockwell College Secondary School, Tipperary

Additional Information

- Excellent computer skills: Microsoft office (Excel, Word, Windows)
- Excellent analytical, judgement and communication skills
- Full Irish Driving Licence
- Hobbies: Gym, Football & Golf
- Interests: Books, Movies & Music

References:

Available on request